<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
    <id>io.github.dlippok.photometric-viewer</id>
    <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.dlippok.photometric-viewer.desktop</launchable>
    <name>Photometric Viewer</name>
    <name xml:lang="de">Photometriebetrachter</name>
    <summary>Browse content of IES and LDT photometric files</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="de">Öffne IES- und LDT-Photometriedateien</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="pl">Przeglądaj zawartość plików fotometrzcznych IES i LDT</summary>
    <description>
        <p>
            Photometric Viewer allow viewing light distribution curves and metadata of IESNA and EULUMDAT photometric
            files which describe the light distribution of light sources like lamps and luminaires and
            are used mostly for data transfer in the lighting industry and in 3D graphics.
        </p>
        <p xml:lang="de">
            Betrachter für Lichtverteilungskurven und Metadaten von IESNA und EULUMDAT Photometriedateien.
            Photometriedateien beschreiben die Lichtverteilung von Lampen und Leuchten und werden vor allem
            für Datentransfer in der Leuchtenindustrire und 3D-Grafik eingesetzt.
        </p>
        <p xml:lang="pl">
            Przeglądarka krzywych fotometrycznych i metadanych plików IESNA i EULUMDAT.
            Pliki fotometryczne zawierają informację o lampach i oprawach oświetleniowych i są używane głównie do
            transferu danych w przemyśle oświetleniowym i grafice 3D.
        </p>
        <p>
            Photometric Viewer displays following information of the opened photometric file:
        </p>
        <p xml:lang="de">
            Photometriebetrachter zeigt folgende Informationen über die Photometiredatei an:
        </p>
        <p xml:lang="pl">
            Aplikacja pozwala zobaczyć następujące informacje zawarte w plikach fotometrycznych:
        </p>
        <ul>
            <li>Light distribution curves</li>
            <li>General information (Catalog Number, Manufacturer, Description, etc.)</li>
            <li>Photometric properties (Light Output Ratio and Downward Flux Fraction)</li>
            <li>Lamps and ballast information</li>
            <li>Luminaire and luminous opening geometry information</li>
            <li>Additional properties (Test number, issue date, test laboratory, etc.)</li>
            <li>Intensity Values for selected C planes and gamma angles</li>
            <li>Raw text source of photometric file</li>
        </ul>
        <ul xml:lang="de">
            <li>Lichtverteilungskurve</li>
            <li>Allgemeine Informationen (Katalognummer, Hersteller, Beschreibung, usw.)</li>
            <li>Photometishce Eigenschaften</li>
            <li>Information über Lampen und Vorschaltgeräte</li>
            <li>Abmessungen der Leuchte und der Lichtaustrittfläche</li>
            <li>Zusätzliche Informationen (Testnummer, Datum, Photometrisches Labor, usw.)</li>
            <li>Candela-Werte für ausgewählte C-Ebenen und Gammawinkel</li>
            <li>Textinhalt der Photometriedatei</li>
        </ul>
        <ul xml:lang="pl">
            <li>Krzywe fotometrzyczne</li>
            <li>Podstawowe informacje (numer katalogowy, producent, opis, itd.)</li>
            <li>Właściwości fotometryczne</li>
            <li>Informacje o lampach i statecznikach</li>
            <li>Wymiary oprawy oświetleniowej i powierzchni świecącej</li>
            <li>Dodatkowe informacje (numer pomiaru, data, laboratorium, itd.)</li>
            <li>Wartości światłości dla wybranych płaszczyzn i kontów gamma</li>
            <li>Żródło pliku fotometrycznego</li>
        </ul>
    </description>
    <screenshots>
        <screenshot>
            <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dlippok/photometric-viewer/master/docs/screenshots/Main.png</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dlippok/photometric-viewer/master/docs/screenshots/Properties.png</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dlippok/photometric-viewer/master/docs/screenshots/Lamps.png</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dlippok/photometric-viewer/master/docs/screenshots/Intensities.png</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dlippok/photometric-viewer/master/docs/screenshots/Source.png</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dlippok/photometric-viewer/master/docs/screenshots/ExportLdc.png</image>
        </screenshot>
    </screenshots>
    <project_license>MIT</project_license>
    <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
    <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/dlippok/photometric-viewer/issues</url>
    <update_contact>mail.dalee_at_gmail.com</update_contact>

    <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />>

    <supports>
        <control>pointing</control>
        <control>keyboard</control>
        <control>touch</control>
    </supports>

    <requires>
        <display_length compare="gt">xsmall</display_length>
        <internet>offline-only</internet>
    </requires>

    <releases>
        <release version="1.5.0" date="2023-10-03">
            <description>
                <p>Reworks luminaire properties page, adds calculation of luminous flux, allows setting properties of exported light distribution curves and fixes various bugs.</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Überarbeitet die Seite mit den Leuchteneigenschaften, fügt die Berechnung des Lichtstroms hinzu, ermöglicht die Einstellung der Eigenschaften von exportierten Lichtverteilungskurven und behebt verschiedene Fehler..</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Przebudowano stronę właściwości oprawy oświetleniowej, dodano obliczanie strumienia świetlnego, umożliwiono ustawianie właściwości eksportowanych krzywych fotometrycznych i naprawiono różne błędy.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.4.0" date="2023-09-01">
            <description>
                <p>Allows exporting photometries as EULUMDAT or IESNA, adds power consumption calculator, Polish translations and fixes minor bugs.</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Ermöglicht den Export von Photometern als EULUMDAT oder IESNA, fügt einen Stromverbrauchsrechner und polnische Übersetzungen hinzu und behebt kleinere Bugs.</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Umożliwia eksport fotometrii jako EULUMDAT lub IESNA, dodaje kalkulator zużycia energii i polskie tłumaczenia i naprawia drobne błędy.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.3.0" date="2023-07-23">
            <description>
                <p>Lets the user configure appearance of photometric diagram, allows opening files via Drag and Drop and fixes various minor bugs.</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Ermöglicht Konfiguration der Lichtverteulungskurve, fügt Support von Drag-and-Drop hinzu und behebt diverse kleinere Fehler.</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Pozwala na konfigurację wyglądu krzywej światłości, umożliwia otwieranie plików przez opuszczenie ich w oknie programu i poprawia drobne błędy.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.2.0" date="2023-07-15">
            <description>
                <p>Allows exporting luminaire data as JSON, intensity values as CSV and light distribution curves as image files. Adds support for complex luminous openings.</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Ermöglicht den Export von Leuchtendaten als JSON, Candela-Werte als CSV und Lichtverteilungskurven als Bilddateien. Fügt Unterstützung für komplexe Lichtöffnungen hinzu.</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Umożliwia eksport danych opraw jako JSON, wartości światłości jako CSV oraz krzywych światłości jako plik graficzny. Wprowadza obsługę skomplikowanych geometrii powierzchni świecących.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.1.0" date="2023-06-27">
            <description>
                <p>Adds support for browsing intensity values in the opened photometric file, includes legend of the photometric curve and introduces German translations for the user interface.</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Ermöglicht Anzeigen von Candela-Werten, fügt eine Legende der Lichtverteilungskurve hinzu und führt deutsche Übersetzungen für die Benutzeroberfläche ein.</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Umożliwia wyświetlanie wartości światłości, dodaje legende do wyświetlanej krzywej oraz tłumaczenie w języku Niemeckim.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.0.1" date="2023-06-24">
            <description>
                <p>Fix bug that prevents opening IES files by double-clicking them in file explorer.</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Behebt einen Fehlers, der das Öffnen von IES-Dateien durch Doppelklicken im Datei-Explorer verhindert.</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Poprawia błąd uniemożliwiający otwieranie plików IES z poziomu przeglądarki plików.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.0.0" date="2023-06-10">
            <description>
                <p>Adds support for EULUMDAT files, introduces extended lamp and geometry information and allows user to select preferred size units.</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Erlaubt das Öffnen von EULUMDAT-Dateien, fügt zusätzliche Informationen zur Lampen- und Leuchtengeometrie und erlaubt dem Benutzer, Längeneinheiten für die Anzeige auszuwählen.</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Wprowadza możliwość otwierania plików EULUMDAT, dodaje informacje o geometrii oprawy i pozwala użytkownikowi wybrać wyświetlane jednostki miar.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="0.2.0" date="2023-05-01">
            <description>
                <p>Adds support for additional luminaire properties and displaying source text of photometric files.</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Fügt neue Leuchteneigenschaften hinzu und ermöglicht die Anzeige der Quelle der Photometriedatei.</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Dodaje nowe właściwości i umożliwia pokazanie kodu źródłowego pliku.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="0.1.0" date="2023-04-07"/>
    </releases>
    <url type="homepage">https://github.com/dlippok/photometric-viewer</url>
</component>
