<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
    <id>io.github.dlippok.photometric-viewer</id>
    <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.dlippok.photometric-viewer.desktop</launchable>
    <name>Photometry</name>
    <name xml:lang="de">Photometrie</name>
    <name xml:lang="pl">Fotometria</name>
    <summary>View photometric files</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="de">Öffne Photometriedateien</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="pl">Przeglądaj pliki fotometryczne</summary>
    <description>
        <p>
            Photometry shows light distribution curves and metadata of IESNA and EULUMDAT photometric
            files which describe the light distribution of light sources like lamps and luminaires and
            are used mostly for data transfer in the lighting industry and in 3D graphics.
        </p>
        <p xml:lang="de">
            Betrachter für Lichtverteilungskurven und Metadaten von IESNA und EULUMDAT Photometriedateien.
            Photometriedateien beschreiben die Lichtverteilung von Lampen und Leuchten und werden vor allem
            für Datentransfer in der Leuchtenindustrire und 3D-Grafik eingesetzt.
        </p>
        <p xml:lang="pl">
            Przeglądarka krzywych fotometrycznych i metadanych plików IESNA i EULUMDAT.
            Pliki fotometryczne zawierają informację o lampach i oprawach oświetleniowych i są używane głównie do
            transferu danych w przemyśle oświetleniowym i grafice 3D.
        </p>
        <p>
            Photometry allows editing the source content of the opened photometric file and shows the following
            information contained in the opened files:
        </p>
        <p xml:lang="de">
            Photometrie erlaubt den Inhalt der Photometriedateien zu bearbeiten und zeigt folgende Informationen an:
        </p>
        <p xml:lang="pl">
            Aplikacja pozwala eytować kod źródłowy plików fotometrycznych oraz przeglądać następujące informacje:
        </p>
        <ul>
            <li>Light distribution curves</li>
            <li xml:lang="de">Lichtverteilungskurve</li>
            <li xml:lang="pl">Krzywe fotometrzyczne</li>
            <li>General information (Catalog Number, Manufacturer, Description, etc.)</li>
            <li xml:lang="de">Allgemeine Informationen (Katalognummer, Hersteller, Beschreibung, usw.)</li>
            <li xml:lang="pl">Podstawowe informacje (numer katalogowy, producent, opis, itd.)</li>
            <li>Photometric properties (Light Output Ratio and Downward Flux Fraction)</li>
            <li xml:lang="de">Photometishce Eigenschaften</li>
            <li xml:lang="pl">Właściwości fotometryczne</li>
            <li>Lamps and ballast information</li>
            <li xml:lang="de">Information über Lampen und Vorschaltgeräte</li>
            <li xml:lang="pl">Informacje o lampach i statecznikach</li>
            <li>Luminaire and luminous opening geometry information</li>
            <li xml:lang="de">Abmessungen der Leuchte und der Lichtaustrittfläche</li>
            <li xml:lang="pl">Wymiary oprawy oświetleniowej i powierzchni świecącej</li>
            <li>Additional properties (Test number, issue date, test laboratory, etc.)</li>
            <li xml:lang="de">Zusätzliche Informationen (Testnummer, Datum, Photometrisches Labor, usw.)</li>
            <li xml:lang="pl">Dodatkowe informacje (numer pomiaru, data, laboratorium, itd.)</li>
            <li>Intensity Values for selected C planes and gamma angles</li>
            <li xml:lang="de">Candela-Werte für ausgewählte C-Ebenen und Gammawinkel</li>
            <li xml:lang="pl">Wartości światłości dla wybranych płaszczyzn i kontów gamma</li>
        </ul>
    </description>
    <branding>
        <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#62a0ea</color>
        <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#1a5fb4</color>
    </branding>
    <screenshots>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dlippok/photometric-viewer/master/docs/screenshots/Main.png</image>
            <caption>Main application window</caption>
            <caption xml:lang="de">Hauptfenster der Anwendung</caption>
            <caption xml:lang="pl">Główne okno aplikacji</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dlippok/photometric-viewer/master/docs/screenshots/Eulumdat.png</image>
            <caption>Editing Eulumdat file</caption>
            <caption xml:lang="de">Eulumdat-Dateien bearbeiten</caption>
            <caption xml:lang="pl">Edycja plików Eulumdat</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dlippok/photometric-viewer/master/docs/screenshots/Lamps.png</image>
            <caption>Lamp imformation</caption>
            <caption xml:lang="de">Lampeninformation</caption>
            <caption xml:lang="pl">Informacje o lampach</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dlippok/photometric-viewer/master/docs/screenshots/Intensities.png</image>
            <caption>Intensity values</caption>
            <caption xml:lang="de">Candela-Werte</caption>
            <caption xml:lang="pl">Wartości światłości</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dlippok/photometric-viewer/master/docs/screenshots/Geometry.png</image>
            <caption>Luminaire Geometry</caption>
            <caption xml:lang="de">Geometrie der Leuchte</caption>
            <caption xml:lang="pl">Geometria oprawy oświetleniowej</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dlippok/photometric-viewer/master/docs/screenshots/ExportLdc.png</image>
            <caption>Export light distribution curve</caption>
            <caption xml:lang="de">Export von Lichtverteilungskurven</caption>
            <caption xml:lang="pl">Eksport krzywej światłości</caption>
        </screenshot>
    </screenshots>
    <project_license>MIT</project_license>
    <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>

    <developer id="io.github.dlippok">
        <name>Damian Lippok</name>
    </developer>
    <update_contact>mail.dalee@gmail.com</update_contact>

    <url type="homepage">https://github.com/dlippok/photometric-viewer</url>
    <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/dlippok/photometric-viewer/issues</url>
    <url type="help">https://github.com/dlippok/photometric-viewer/discussions/categories/q-a</url>

    <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>

    <supports>
        <control>pointing</control>
        <control>keyboard</control>
        <control>touch</control>
    </supports>

    <recommends>
        <display_length compare="ge">600</display_length>
    </recommends>

    <requires>
        <display_length compare="gt">360</display_length>
        <internet>offline-only</internet>
    </requires>

    <releases>
        <release version="3.4.0" date="2026-01-18">
           <description>
                <p>Uses GNOME runtime version 49</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Verwendet GNOME-Laufzeitumgebung Version 49</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Używa środowiska GNOME w wersji 49</p>
           </description>
        </release>
        <release version="3.3.0" date="2024-12-29">
           <description>
                <p>Quick calculation of required number of luminaires for illuminated zones.</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Überschlagsrechung der Leuchtenanzahl für zu beleuchtende Bereiche.</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Przybliżone obliczenie potrzebnej liczby opraw dla oświetlanego obszaru.</p>
           </description>
        </release>
        <release version="3.2.1" date="2024-11-24">
           <description>
                <p>Uses GNOME runtime version 47</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Verwendet GNOME-Laufzeitumgebung Version 47</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Używa środowiska GNOME w wersji 47</p>
           </description>
        </release>
        <release version="3.2.0" date="2024-08-19">
            <description>
                <p>Introduces sidebar layout for editing sources of photometric files.</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Es wird eines Sidebar-Layouts eingeführt, um das Bearbeiten von Quellen der photometrischen Dateien zu vereinfachen.</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Dodaje layout z użyciem paska bocznego do edycji źródeł plików fotometrycznych.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="3.1.0" date="2024-07-13">
            <description>
                <p>Adds autosave support</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Fügt Unterstützung für automatisches Speichern hinzu</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Dodaje obsługę automatycznego zapisu</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="3.0.0" date="2024-05-28">
            <description>
                <p>Allow editing the content of opened photometric files</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Ermöglicht die Bearbeitung des Inhalts von geöffneten photometrischen Dateien</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Umożliwienie edycji zawartości otwartych plików fotometrycznych</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.1.3" date="2024-04-04">
            <description>
                <p>Fixed translations of application description</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Korrigiert Übersetzungen der Anwendungsbeschreibung</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Poprawiono tłumaczenia opisu aplikacji</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.1.2" date="2024-03-29">
            <description>
                <p>Display direct ratios for room indices, cleanup main content page and fix crashes when opening incomplete or faulty photometric files.</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Fügt Anzeige für Direkt-Nutzlichtstrom-Anteile für Raumindizien, bereinigt die Hauptinhaltsseite und behebt abstürze beim Öffnen unvollständiger oder fehlerhafter Photometriedateien.</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Dodano wskaźniki pomieszczeń dla obliczeń metodą lumenów, uproszczono stronę główną i naprawiono otwieranie niekompletnych lub błędnych plików fotometrycznych.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.1.1" date="2024-01-27">
            <description>
                <p>Fixed bug preventing the application from starting when installed via Flathub.</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Es wurde ein Fehler behoben, der den Start der Anwendung verhinderte, wenn das Programm über Flathub installiert wurde.</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Naprawiono błąd uniemożliwiający uruchomienie aplikacji po zainstalowaniu jej przez Flathub.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.1.0" date="2024-01-21">
            <description>
                <p>Adds syntax highlighting for source text of photometric files and a button for opening of URLs from attributes of IES files in a web browser. Includes various minor bugfixes.</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Fügt Syntax-Hervorhebung für den Quelltext photometrischer Dateien und eine Schaltfläche zum Öffnen von URLs aus Attributen von IES-Dateien in einem Webbrowser hinzu. Enthält verschiedene kleinere Bugfixes.</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Dodano podświetlanie składni dla tekstu źródłowego plików fotometrycznych oraz przycisk do otwierania adresów URL zawartych w atrybutach plików IES w przeglądarce internetowej. Zawiera różne drobne poprawki błędów.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.0.0" date="2024-01-13">
            <description>
                <p>Rebranding of the application to Photometry with improved application icon.</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Umbenennung der Anwendung in "Photometrie" mit verbessertem Anwendungssymbol.</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Zmiana marki na "Fotometria" z nowa ikoną aplikacji.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.6.1" date="2023-12-03">
            <description>
                <p>Fixes crash when opening photometric files using the button on the start page.</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Behebt Absturz beim Öffnen von Photometrie-Dateien über den Button auf der Startseite.</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Naprawiono błąd podczas otwierania plików fotometrycznych za pomocą przycisku na stronie startowej.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.6.0" date="2023-11-25">
            <description>
                <p>Adds luminous efficacy and descriptions for photometric values for beginners</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Fügt Anzeige für Lichtausbeute und Beschreibungen für photometrische Werte für Anfänger hinzu</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Dodano skuteczność świetlną i opisy wartości fotometrycznych dla początkujących.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.5.1" date="2023-10-03">
            <description>
                <p>Fix bug preventing running application from Snap package</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Fehler behoben, der die Ausführung von Anwendungen aus dem Snap-Paket verhindert</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Naprawiono błąd uniemożliwiający uruchomienie aplikacji z pakietu Snap</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.5.0" date="2023-10-03">
            <description>
                <p>Reworks luminaire properties page, adds calculation of luminous flux, allows setting properties of exported light distribution curves and fixes various bugs.</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Überarbeitet die Seite mit den Leuchteneigenschaften, fügt die Berechnung des Lichtstroms hinzu, ermöglicht die Einstellung der Eigenschaften von exportierten Lichtverteilungskurven und behebt verschiedene Fehler..</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Przebudowano stronę właściwości oprawy oświetleniowej, dodano obliczanie strumienia świetlnego, umożliwiono ustawianie właściwości eksportowanych krzywych fotometrycznych i naprawiono różne błędy.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.4.0" date="2023-09-01">
            <description>
                <p>Allows exporting photometries as EULUMDAT or IESNA, adds power consumption calculator, Polish translations and fixes minor bugs.</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Ermöglicht den Export von Photometern als EULUMDAT oder IESNA, fügt einen Stromverbrauchsrechner und polnische Übersetzungen hinzu und behebt kleinere Bugs.</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Umożliwia eksport fotometrii jako EULUMDAT lub IESNA, dodaje kalkulator zużycia energii i polskie tłumaczenia i naprawia drobne błędy.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.3.0" date="2023-07-23">
            <description>
                <p>Lets the user configure appearance of photometric diagram, allows opening files via Drag and Drop and fixes various minor bugs.</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Ermöglicht Konfiguration der Lichtverteulungskurve, fügt Support von Drag-and-Drop hinzu und behebt diverse kleinere Fehler.</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Pozwala na konfigurację wyglądu krzywej światłości, umożliwia otwieranie plików przez opuszczenie ich w oknie programu i poprawia drobne błędy.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.2.0" date="2023-07-15">
            <description>
                <p>Allows exporting luminaire data as JSON, intensity values as CSV and light distribution curves as image files. Adds support for complex luminous openings.</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Ermöglicht den Export von Leuchtendaten als JSON, Candela-Werte als CSV und Lichtverteilungskurven als Bilddateien. Fügt Unterstützung für komplexe Lichtöffnungen hinzu.</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Umożliwia eksport danych opraw jako JSON, wartości światłości jako CSV oraz krzywych światłości jako plik graficzny. Wprowadza obsługę skomplikowanych geometrii powierzchni świecących.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.1.0" date="2023-06-27">
            <description>
                <p>Adds support for browsing intensity values in the opened photometric file, includes legend of the photometric curve and introduces German translations for the user interface.</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Ermöglicht Anzeigen von Candela-Werten, fügt eine Legende der Lichtverteilungskurve hinzu und führt deutsche Übersetzungen für die Benutzeroberfläche ein.</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Umożliwia wyświetlanie wartości światłości, dodaje legende do wyświetlanej krzywej oraz tłumaczenie w języku Niemeckim.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.0.1" date="2023-06-24">
            <description>
                <p>Fix bug that prevents opening IES files by double-clicking them in file explorer.</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Behebt einen Fehlers, der das Öffnen von IES-Dateien durch Doppelklicken im Datei-Explorer verhindert.</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Poprawia błąd uniemożliwiający otwieranie plików IES z poziomu przeglądarki plików.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.0.0" date="2023-06-10">
            <description>
                <p>Adds support for EULUMDAT files, introduces extended lamp and geometry information and allows user to select preferred size units.</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Erlaubt das Öffnen von EULUMDAT-Dateien, fügt zusätzliche Informationen zur Lampen- und Leuchtengeometrie und erlaubt dem Benutzer, Längeneinheiten für die Anzeige auszuwählen.</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Wprowadza możliwość otwierania plików EULUMDAT, dodaje informacje o geometrii oprawy i pozwala użytkownikowi wybrać wyświetlane jednostki miar.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="0.2.0" date="2023-05-01">
            <description>
                <p>Adds support for additional luminaire properties and displaying source text of photometric files.</p>
                <p xml:lang="de">Fügt neue Leuchteneigenschaften hinzu und ermöglicht die Anzeige der Quelle der Photometriedatei.</p>
                <p xml:lang="pl">Dodaje nowe właściwości i umożliwia pokazanie kodu źródłowego pliku.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="0.1.0" date="2023-04-07"/>
    </releases>
</component>

